Kira R. Mills

University of Texas at Dallas Richardson, TX

Phone: (813) 416-7956 Email: KiraRMills@gmail.com

PhD student using Molecular Dynamics simulations to study substrate specificity of proteins and use it for smarter molecular design. Passionate about communication at the teaching, research, and public level, and at improving the accessibility of science and higher education to all communities.

EDUCATION

2018 - Present **PhD - Chemistry**

University of Texas at Dallas

- Advisor: Dr. Steven Nielsen

- Research Area: Computational chemistry to study proteins

B.S. - Chemistry, Magna Cum Laude

2013 - 2018

Texas A&M University - Commerce

- Advisor: Dr. Bukuo Ni

- Research Area: Organic synthesis

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant 2018 - Present

General Chemistry, University of Texas at Dallas

- Aiding student comprehension of concepts in general chemistry and introductory lab techniques
- Working with instructors and lab coordinator to modify curriculum to improve student comprehension
- Recognizing common student pitfalls and developing preventative measures to implement during lab period

Chemistry & Physics Tutor

2015 - 2018

Texas A&M University - Commerce

- Taught students in both one-on-one and group settings concepts of introductory chemistry and physics
- Worked with professors to improve mandatory student workshops
- Attended and presented at Student Success conference to improve communication skills in STEM students

Ronald E. McNair Scholar

2016 - 2018

Texas A&M University - Commerce

- Developed a 10-week research project in organic synthesis
- Attended and presented at several conferences
- Worked to aid understanding of why research is important and what unique struggles underrepresented groups face

Peer Mentor 2017 - 2018

Texas A&M University - Commerce

- Taught curriculum for a once a week class which covered topics related to freshmen success
- Encouraged student involvement in on-campus activities and organizations
- Connected students to important resources when necessary

PRESENTATIONS

255th ACS National Meeting	March 2018
Oral Presentation: "Diarylpyrolinol silyl ether as organocatalyst for asymmetric cycloaddition to produce spirocyclic δ -lactones"	
Texas National McNair Research Conference	February 2018
Oral Presentation: "Synthesis of spirocyclic δ -lactones by asymmetric organocatalytic reactions"	
14 th Annual Pathways Student Research Symposium	November 2017
Poster Presentation: "Synthesis of spirocyclic δ-lactones"	
2017 ACS Southwest Regional Meeting (SWRM)	October 2017
Poster Presentation: "Synthesis of spirocyclic δ-lactones"	
TRiO - McNair Scholars Showcase	October 2017
Oral Presentation: "Synthesis of spirocyclic δ-lactones"	
Gulf Coast Student Success Conference	November 2016
Oral Presentation: "Teaching Scientific Writing, Even as a Non-STEM Peer Educator"	